Riley Soloner

New York, NY | 510.717.8226 | rileysoloner@gmail.com LinkedIn | Github | Blog | Portfolio

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Full Stack Developer with experience using JavaScript, React, and Ruby on Rails with 15 years experience as a comedy writer/performer. Enthusiastic about using tech as a tool for creativity. I bring strong skills in collaboration, communication and building relationships.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript, React, HTML/CSS, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, PostGreSQL, SQL, RESTful APIs, Object-Oriented Programming, Git, Github, Version Control, Adobe Premiere, Figma

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Story Outliner - Github | Demo

Outline and visualize the narrative arc of your next chapter, episode, or story.

- Designed a wireframe on Excalidraw to plan and pitch the project concept
- Styled front end with ReactSuite and custom CSS
- Developed a JSON API back end to save and display submissions on a gallery page

Troll Simulator v. 1.0 Beta Beta - Github | Demo

Comedic story-based website "written for and by trolls."

- Co-authored a "choose your own adventure" tree using UseState and React Router Dom
- Styled front end with custom CSS
- Developed a JSON API back end guestbook to log uploaded user profiles

Haiku Reviews - Github

Post and read movie reviews written as haiku poems.

- Built with Ruby on Rails and React
- Adhered to RESTful conventions, applied MVC pattern & CRUD functionality for core resources
- Styled front end with custom CSS

EXPERIENCE

Cutting Edge Elite, Inc., New York, NY

August 2015 - February 2020

Team Lieutenant

- Handled communication between catering management, clients and staff
- Managed teams of hospitality professionals

Upright Citizens Brigade Theatre, New York, NY

January 2008 - March 2020

Writer, Performer, Producer

- Performed in hundreds of theatrical improvisation, sketch and solo shows
- Developed a repertoire of marketable characters
- Directed, coached and mentored developing teams and performers

EDUCATION

Flatiron School, New York, NY

June 2022 - October 2022

Software Engineering Bootcamp (In-person) - Full Stack Web Development